Varun Nadgir

Data Scientist | Data Analyst | Data Engineer

I am a problem solver skilled in SQL, Python, R, and Excel, with experience using various machine learning and data visualization packages to clean, analyze, and present data. Having worked as a data analyst and math tutor, I am comfortable with public speaking and giving presentations, and I strive to make the data understandable for all levels of knowledge. My interests are in machine learning and data visualizations.

vanadgir@gmail.com

(508) 615-8646

Maynard, MA, USA



www.varun.pro/



in linkedin.com/in/varun-nadgir

SKILLS

MS SQL Server

Database Management

Python pandas scikit-learn

NumPy

Matplotlib

ggplot2

Machine Learning

Regression

Clustering

Classification

Reporting

Data Visualization

Data Wrangling

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate, Operations & IT

Beacon Pointe Wealth Advisors

02/2019 - 04/2020 Achievements/Tasks

Maintained and audited database of ~24,000 active accounts, with 30-50 new accounts feeding in daily, amounting to ~\$11B AUM.

- Created on-demand reports for internal operations, and modified financial reports to meet advisors' needs and reconcile account performance.
- Provided IT support to over 160 employees across 10+ partner offices nationwide (with occasional travel).

Analyst

Findability Sciences

10/2015 - 02/2017 Remote

Achievements/Tasks

- Wrote SQL queries needed to populate back-end database in Microsoft SQL Server, while also performing daily data cleaning to account for changes in company policies, naming schema, and potential errors.
- Helped clients visualize their donor behaviors by developing and updating an online UI, increasing donor retention by about 15% in the first year of the 3-year project.

Instructor iGradeEdu

04/2015 - 02/2017

Remote

Waltham, MA

Achievements/Tasks

- Prepared online mathematics lessons for students ranging from 4th to 10th grade, including one online tournament for multiple high schools participating remotely
- Strengthened the presentation skills necessary for explaining concepts to those unfamiliar with a particular subject.

EDUCATION

BS Mathematics

University of Massachusetts, Amherst

Amherst, MA

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Music Recommendation System (2021)

- Using sklearn, built a combination of collaborative filtering and matrix factorization models to recommend songs based on similarity
- Documented entire code base for presentation and review purposes, prioritizing readability and reproducibility

Esports Statistics: League of Legends (2018)

- Studied the behaviors of professional teams/players to explore what strategies are successful, using Python libraries such as pandas, numpy, scipy, and matplotlib
- Built a logistic regression model to predict the outcome of a match

Improving the Services of The College Scorecard (2017)

- Employed linear regression models and clustering algorithms to build cost prediction and college recommendation tools using R